Let's talk about travel. Tell me about
the last place that you went to. The
last place that I traveled to was
Thailand, Bangkok to be specific.
Um big city, but also has um places that
are close by that you can travel to that
are not cities. It's more countryside or
nature like Krabi. Um
one of my favorite countries in the
world.
It has the best food, the best people,
quite multicultural,
and uh just fun experiences. It has
something for everyone, whether you're a
man, woman, old, young. Um
you can find something to do in a city
like Bangkok or in a country like
Thailand. So, would you prefer a city
break or a beach holiday?
>> Definitely a beach holiday because um I
grew up in a city, and although it has
its perks,
I feel like sometimes it can be too
much. So, when I like to get away, it's
definitely to something that's more
nature and hence a beach holiday. Sun,
sand, the ocean, peace, quiet, the slow
life is definitely something that I like
to get away to. Is there anywhere you
haven't been yet that you would love to
go to? Several places. Istanbul, Turkey,
is at the top of that list. I haven't
been to the Philippines. I'd really like
to go to the Philippines. Um yeah,
um yeah, very many places that I I
haven't been to. I'm a I'm a huge fan of
uh different cultures. So,
any chance that I get,
I'm
excited to get out of my hometown and go
visit other places. Now, let's talk
about the future. In 10 years' time,
what job would you like to have? I would
like to have my own business. I'm a
closeted entrepreneur. So, um
and it's always been my dream to be able
to have a business of my own.
Um
hopefully in the home design buying and
selling space.
Uh I have a passion for interior design
on the on a separate note.
But yes, uh
a businesswoman
is definitely something that I hope I'm
able to be in the next 10 years.
And will English be useful in your
future career? Yes.
Uh where I come from, English is a very
commonly spoken language and the places
that I see myself living in, uh English
is the official language. So,
English would not only be useful, it
would be necessary
for me specifically. So,
yes. And in your future career, would
you like to travel a lot or would you
like to be in one location? I think when
I have children, I will slow down the
traveling a little bit just to have some
structure and uh
a feeling of groundedness in their
lives, especially when they're younger.
But
up until then, in the near future,
because I don't have any children at the
moment, um I would love to travel as
much as possible. So, a bit of both, I
would say.
How do you think your life will change
over the coming 5 to 10 years? I don't
know about how it would change, but I
know how
I want it to change. I would like to get
married. I would like to start
a small family, and by small I mean have
three daughters.
Um that's big to some people.
Uh I would like to start a business of
my own.
And I would like to retire my parents
and see them uh take care of their
health and grow
older in a safe place.
And um
yeah, and just be healthy, happy,
wiser, hopefully. Now, let's talk about
social media. Which social media sites
do you use the most? Um Before we
continue, I have a gift for you. I've
analyzed hundreds of band nine
transcripts from our successful VIP
students and I put the 100 most used
words into a PDF for you. If you want
that, go to the description or the
pinned comment. You can download it for
free. Instagram. It's my most frequently
used. I think it's the only one unless
YouTube counts as social media, which in
that case YouTube as well. And how much
time do you spend on those social media
sites? It depends on the day. So, on
busy days when I'm working, I don't get
a chance to spend too long on my phone
or any social media in general. And then
on the weekend when I'm
rotting on my couch, uh I can doom
scroll for sometimes a couple hours.
What kind of information do you feel
comfortable and uncomfortable putting on
social media? I feel uncomfortable
posting anything any personal
information. So, I don't like posting
anything about my family,
about my relationships, about too much
about my friendships.
I'm just not somebody I'm private, so I
don't like to post too much about it
on social media, but
um if it's something related to work,
something that I can benefit off of
using using social media to promote
something or promote something that my
friend's doing or you know, just get
more eyeballs on something,
um
I'm happy to post that on social media.
And is there anything that you dislike
about social media? Yes, very many
things. I think sometimes social media
can have a very negative effect on your
mental health.
Sometimes sitting behind a screen and
looking at the highlights of everyone
else's life
makes you feel like you're not doing
enough because you see
all the things that people are doing
whether it's someone looking really good
or someone getting married or someone
buying a new house or a new car.
And it kind of gives you a skewed
perception of someone's life without
showing you the negative things.
And it's very easy to spiral and feel
like everybody health else has
a fantastic life and I'm here and I have
these problems and why isn't it working
out for me? And I think that's not a
very fair representation of reality. A
website that I bought something recently
from is called Etsy, etsy.com to be
specific. Um I bought a
Oh, sorry. The website is basically uh a
place where you can go and buy things
from small businesses or people that run
businesses from their houses.
So it's uh art, craft. It's like very
niche uh
things that you can buy like keychains,
mugs.
And more importantly, it's from small
businesses and um
stay-at-home moms and that kind of vibe
if that makes sense. What I bought was a
dog bed for my dog. It was customizable,
so I could get the size that I wanted
and I could get the color that I wanted
and get a custom dog tag.
Um
I loved it. I loved it because um
not only was it something that
uh I needed,
it fit my home aesthetically
in every way because it was it I could
pick out the color, I could pick out the
texture, I could pick out the height,
the width, everything. My dog loves it,
needless to say, she doesn't sleep
anywhere else other than the bed. She's
on it. She's probably on it right now.
When I go home, I'll see her on it. Uh I
also like the fact that I could support
small businesses. I hope to be a
business owner in the future, so I like
to support small businesses over
big corporations and
>> end of part two. So, we've been talking
about a website that you bought
something from and we're going to
continue to talk about shopping online
and online business. In your country,
what are the most popular things people
buy online? Everything. We buy groceries
online, we buy electronics online,
clothes, bags, shoes.
Um
Amazon is probably the most famous
website that you can buy things on.
And uh our entire I don't think people
go to stores anymore. It's very uh
especially our generation. I think
online shopping you can buy everything
online. And why has online shopping
become so popular in your particular
country? It can be quite overwhelming in
a place like India in the big cities to
kind of go through all the the stores.
It's a lot of stimulus and it takes a
lot of effort to do it because there's a
lot of people and
it's a lot of interaction with people.
It's a little bit noisy and it's you
know
um
So, I think our generation we're a bit
uh
Mm. I don't want to say introverted, but
we like uh uh uh
personal space a little bit more. So,
just the convenience of having
being able to click things on a screen
and have it shipped to your house and
not having to interact with people is
very enticing.
So, um for those reasons I think people
prefer to buy things online more than in
store. Are there any possible
disadvantages of the growth of online
shopping? Perhaps
um
in terms of how it may pollute the
environment and I say that only because
when you buy something online
usually with the big corporations they
have a pretty good return policy
and although that's very handy as a
consumer
a lot of people take advantage of it and
they order things that they don't need
and
return it just to be able to return it.
Um and uh I think that in terms of
delivery, in terms of packaging, in
terms of shipping,
uh
in general, I think it can cause a lot
of uh
pollution to the environment that you
don't need. If you go to a store and
pick up a shirt, you can just pick it
up, put it in a bag, and bring it home.
But, if the same shirt gets shipped to
you, it comes in a lot more excessive
packaging than is necessary.
Um
can be quite uh damaging, a lot of
waste. Do you think it's justified that
some brands charge more for you to
purchase something in store compared to
online? It depends. I think uh for to be
able to buy something in store, if
they're able to create a certain
experience that differentiates
the the buying experience from a
consumer's point of view,
it would make sense. Um
but I imagine
if you're going to get the same product
online and in store,
although I understand it from the
business's perspective that that's a
brick-and-mortar store has a lot more
overheads that they have to worry about,
thinking about it from a consumer's
point of view,
if you can buy the same product online
and in store, and there's no difference
in the experience, as a matter of fact,
it's perhaps a bit more of an
inconvenience to go to a store, I don't
see why it should cost more. And do you
think that in the future shopping malls
will continue to be popular or will they
be less popular because of online
shopping? I think it depends on the
place. In certain places, I recently
visited Dubai, um and shopping malls are
uh a part of the culture because they
have such um extreme weather for many
months of the year.
Malls are where people are able to spend
a lot of their times when the outside
weather conditions aren't as good. And I
imagine that's the case for places where
there's torrential rain in the monsoon
season or it's really hot in the summer
or really cold in the winter.
It's It's It has everything. It has
food, shopping, entertainment. So, I
don't see it being something that will
go out of style in a lot of places.
Um but I don't think that it will
compete with online. I think online in
the long term will continue to grow
even more. And do you think some
businesses in the future, for example,
banks or travel agents will go 100%
online? I don't know about 100%,
but I would say pretty darn close. A lot
of the services that are offered by
banks and travel agencies can be quite
efficiently executed online.
So, I'm trying to think of why there
would be a reason At least travel
agencies, I couldn't think of a reason
why they would need to have a physical
store.
Um With banks, they can have maybe a
small section for their VIP clientele.
But
I would say pretty close to 100% of it
can be
executed online. I'll leave the 1% for
any extrane- extraneous variables that
um I I can't think of at the moment.
Very good. That's the end of the test.
If you want to hear Priyanka again, we
have two more speaking tests including
some where I give detailed feedback on
her performance. Check out this one or
this one.